Register of the United States Army European Command, Historical Division Typescript Studies, 1945-1954
Hoover Institution Archives
- D-Series Manuscripts. (Box 30-34)
  - D-004 Sicilian Campaign: Special Problems and Their Solution (Jul.-Aug. 1943). By Generalmajor Max Ulrch; 11 pp; 1947. A critique of improvised defense methods. Of limited value. (Box 30)
  - D-008 Designation of OB Sued as Sue as Supreme Commander Mediterranean Theater (Sep. 1942). By General der Flieger Paul Deichmann; 34 pp; 1947. A review of eve is and a discussion of problems encountered at a high-level joint headquarters. Included as Volume III in MS # T-3; also available as a separate study. (German version not available in USAREUR.) (Box 30)
  - D-009* Panzer Group Africa Engineer Officer (26 Aug.-Sep. 1941). By Generalmajor Gerhard Jordan, 10 pp, illus; 1947. Interesting side-lights on the Siege of Tobruk, activities of the theater headquarters, and German- Italian relations. (Not translated-1954.) (Box 30)
  - D-010 Rail Transportation Problems in Italy. By Generalmajor Karl Theodor Koerner; 18 pp; 1947. (Box 30)
  - D-013 Construction of Strategic Field Fortifications in Italy (Sep. 1943-Oct. 1944.) Part 1. By Generalmajor Hans Bessel; 13 pp; .1947. Technical. (Box 30)
  - D-019 Clothing and Equipment in Snow and Extreme Cold. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 9 pp; 1947. Based on German experience in Russia. (Box 30)
  - D-020 Field Expedients, Russia. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 10 pp; 1947. Technical improvisations in the field. (Box 30)
  - D-024* Reasons for Rommel's Success in Africa 194-42. By Generalmajor Hans-Hennig von Holzendorff; 41 pp, 9 illus; 1947. Evaluation of Field Marshal Rommel as a commander. (Box 30)
  - D-026 LXXV Corps Artillery on the Ligurian Coast (Apr.-Jul. 1944). By Generalmajor Dr. Heinrich Hoffmann; 13 pp, 2 illus; 1947. (Box 30)
  - D-029 Italian War Production (Sep. 1941-Apr. 1945). By Generalmajor Ernst von Horstig; 50 pp, 4 illus; 1947. Activities of the German chief of military economy in Italy. Comments on Italian-German cooperation. (Not translated-1954.) (Box 30)
  - D-031 Antiaircraft Artillery Fire Against Formations at High Altitudes. By General der Flakartillerie Walter von Axthelm; 5 pp, 2 illus; 1947. A technicial report on the double fuze; its use in the defense of Germany, beginning in autumn 1944. (Box 30)
  - D-033 The Influence of Terrain, Seaasons, and Weather on Operations in Russia. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 11 pp; 1947. (Box 30)
  - D-034 Diseases of Men and Horses Experienced by the Troops in Russia. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 9 pp; 1947. (Box 30)
  - D-035 The Effect of Extreme Cold on Weapons, Wheeled Vehicles and Tracked Vehicles. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 3 pp; 1947. A supplement to MS # D-033. (Box 30)
  - D-036 The Fighting Qualities of the Russian Soldier. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 10 pp; Hist Div USAREUR multilith, Vol. II, No. 8; 1953. Based on personal experience. (Box 31)
  - D-037 Concept and Formation of the Reich Labor Service. By Reichsarbeitsfuhrer Konstantin Hierl; 66 pp, 3 illus; 1947. A discussion of organization and leadership, by its former chief. (Box 31)
  - D-039 Liaison Officer from A-4 of the Second Air Fleet with the G-4 of Commander-in-Chief South. By Generalmajor Wilhelm Merz; 3 pp, 1 illus; 1947. A report on the author's activities. (Box 31)
  - D-040 Negotiations with the Representative of General Barre and the Resident of Tunis, Admiral Esteva. By Generaloberst Bruno Loezer; 4 pp; 1947. Personal recollections. (Box 31)
  - D-042 The Role of Searchlights in World War II. By General der Flakartillerie Walther von Axthelm; 7 pp; 1947. Development, tactical employment, and future value. (Box 31)
  - D-044 Effect of Allied Air Attacks on the Verona Area and the Brenner Pass from the End of April 1944 to 25 April 1945. By Generalleutnant Hermann Hoegner; 14 pp; 1947. (Box 31)
  - D-046 Studies on the Mareth Position--Part II: Survey and Construction. By Generalmajor Fritz Krause; 10 pp, 1 illus; 1947. Non-technical. (Box 31)
  - D-047 Air Transport of 104th Armored Infantry Regiment to Tobruk (Apr. 1941). By Major Werner Reissmann; 6 pp; 1947. From Italy to Africa. (Box 31)
  - D-048 Experience Gained in Fighting Large Fires Resulting from Air Warfare. By Generalleutnant Dr. Johannes Mayer; 24 pp; 1947. Technical. (Box 31)
  - D-049 Railroad Situation from January 1944 to the Beginning of May Offensive (Italy). By Oberst i.G. Klaus Stange; 11 pp; 1947. (Box 31)
  - D-050 Employment of Flak in an Army Defense Zone. By Generalleutnant Werner Prellberg; 23 pp; 1947. Antiaircraft and antitank tactics. (Box 31)
  - D-052 Command in Critical Situations. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 11 pp, 1 illus; OCMH multilith; 1947. An interesting tactical situation at Kozel'sk, 9-11 Oct. 1941. (Box 31)
  - D-053 Russian Command: The 13th Russian Cavalry Division in Action at Kozel'sk. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 11 pp, 1 illus; 1947. A Supplement to MS # D-052. (Box 31)
  - D-054 War Experiences in Russia, Chapter IV: Kirov and the 40-km. Gap: Experiences as Commandant at Roslavl. By General der Infantrie Walter von Unruh; 19 pp; 1947. A personal report. (Box 31)
  - D-056 War Experiences in Russia, Chapter I: Commander of Brest-Litovsk; Chapter II, Commander of the Fourth Army Rear Area. By General der Infanterie Walter von Unruh; 47 pp; 1947. Communications zone activities. (Box 31)
  - D-061 The Estonian Contingents in 1944-45. By General der Artillerie Hans Speth; 3 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. Historical account and evaluation. (Box 31)
  - D-064 First Stuka Wing (Feb.-May 1941). By Generalmajor Hans-Joachim Rath; 5 pp; 1947. Malta and Crete. (Box 31)
  - D-065 Preparations for the Commitment of Parachute and Other Airborne Units in the Projects Invasion of Malta (Jun. 1942). By Generalleutnant Gerhard Conrad; 5 pp; 1947. (Box 31)
  - D-066 Situation in OKW (Oct.-Dec. 1942). By Generalmajor Eckhard Christian; 16 pp; 1947. The Wehrmacht High Command before, during, and after the Allied landing in North Africa, Nov. 1942. (Box 31)
  - D-071 Supply by Air of the Enlarged Bridgehead of Tunis (1 Dec. 1942-11 May 1943). By Generalleutnant Ulrich Buchholz; 18 pp, 3 illus; 1947. (Box 31)
  - D-072 Report on My Activities as Commander of Rear Area of Army of North Africa. By Generalmajor Ernst Schnarrenberger; 15 pp; 1947. Part II, Nov. 1942-Apr. 1943. Historical. (Box 31)
  - D-074 Part Played by the 187th Infantry Regiment in the 87th Infantry Division's Attack at the Beginning of the Russian Campaign on 23 June 1941. By Generalleutnant Hans Bergen; 29 pp, 2 illus; OCMH multilith; 1947. Organization, preparation, and execution of a river crossing against weak enemy resistance. Includes comments on infantry organization. (Box 31)
  - D-075 Encirclement and Annihilation of the Russian 32d Cossack Division (6 and 7 Aug. 1941). By Generalleutnant Hans Bergen; 25 pp, 1 illus; OCMH multilith; 1947. (Box 31)
  - D-076 An Army Engineer in Russia (1942). By Generalmajor Erich Abberger; 25 pp, 5 illus; 1947. A study by the Eleventh Army chief engineer officer, describing the general situation and special problems on the Leningrad front. (Not translated--1954.) (Box 31)
  - D-077 A Reflection on the Causes of the Defeat. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 18 pp; 1947. Military reasons for Germany's defeat. (Box 31)
  - D-078 Winter Fighting of the 253d Infantry Division in the Rzhev Area. By General der Infanterie Otto Schellert; 27 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. A narrative account of action from October 1941 to March 1942, including comments on winter combat. (Box 31)
  - D-079 Advance and Breakthrough of the 6th Panzer Division on 15 and 16 July 1944. By Generalleutnant Rudolf von Waldenfels; 9 pp, 1 illus; multilith by 525th MIS Group; 1947. Relief of encircled forces west of Vilno. (Box 31)
  - D-080 Cancelled. (Box 31)
  - D-080a The Command Decision. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 31 pp, 2 illus; OCMH multilith; 1947. A theoretical study illustrated by a tactical example (Rogachev, 1941). (Box 31)
  - D-093 Railroad, Sea and Air Transport Situation for Supply of Africa Through Italy (Jan.-May 1943). By Generalmajor Conrad Seibt; 8 pp; 1947. Evaluation of the logistical situation in Africa. (Box 31)
  - D-095 29th Panzer Grenadier Division (30 Jul. 1943). By Generalmajor Max Ulrich; 2 pp, 1 illus; 1947. German counterattack at Motta, Sicily. (Not translated--1954.) (Box 31)
  - D-097 Horses in the Russian Campaign. By Dr. Lukas Schaefer and Dr. Kurt Seifert; 7 pp; 1947. Forage, feed, water; preparation for the winter. (Box 31)
  - D-101 46th Infantry Division (1-2 Sep. 1942). By General der Infanterie Franz Mattenklott; 4 pp; 1947. Amphibious attack across the Kerch Straits. (Not translated--1954; not available in USAREUR.) (Box 31)
  - D-102 Protection of Lines of Communications in the East (1 Sep. 1941-Feb. 1943). By Generalmajor Gustav von Bechtolsheim; 7 pp; 1947. Sector of Rear Area Commander, Army Group Center; defense against partisans. (Box 31)
  - D-103 132d Infantry Division--Geo-military Description of the Western Ukraine--The Russian Soldier. By Generalleutnant Rudolf Sintzenich; 8 pp, 2 illus; 1947. A study by a front-line commander. (Box 31)
  - D-106 Combat in Deep Snow. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 17 pp; 1947. March and combat problems; a short resume of the 1941-42 and 1942-43 winter campaigns in Russia. (Box 31)
  - D-107 Tactical Principles of Mountain Warfare. By Generalleutnant Heinrich Greigner; 13 pp; 1947. General doctrine; suggestions based on personal experience. (Box 31)
  - D-109 Security Measures Against Strikes. By Generalleutnant der Polizei Walther Junecke; 30 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. Organization and activities of the German "Technical Emergency Service." (Box 31)
  - D-110 Officer Procurement, World War II. By Generalmajor Helmuth Bachelin; 48 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. (Box 32)
  - D-111 Organization of Air Defense in the Field: Experiences of I Flak Corps. By Generaloberst H. Weise; 15 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. Reasons for the organization of large unified antiaircraft forces for commitment at the point of main effort. Includes three examples from the Western Campaign, 1940. (Box 32)
  - D-116 Overall Situation in the Mediterranean up to the Landing on the Italian Mainland. By Generaloberst Heinrich von Vietinghoff; 7 pp; 1947. Also included in MS # T-1a, Chapter VI. (Box 32)
  - D-120 The Development of the Situation in North Africa (1 Jan.-28 Feb. 1943). By General der Panzertruppen Walter Nehring; 14 pp; 1947. Extracts from the war diary of the deputy chief, Wehrmacht Operations Staff. (Box 32)
  - D-125 Relationship Between Operations and Supply in Africa (Jan. 1943). By Major Richard Feige; 14 pp; 1947. Effect of supply on strategic planning. (Box 32)
  - D-129 Fighting During Retreat of XXVI Corps to Pskov, Feb. 1944. By General der Infanterie Anton Grasser; 7 pp; 1947. (Box 32)
  - D-130 Second Army Gets Out of the Mud. By General der Kavallerie Gustav Harteneck; 19 pp0, 1 illus; OCMH multilith; 1947. A vivid picture of the difficulties and hardships of the muddy season in Russia (Kiev, Orel areas). (Box 32)
  - D-131 Combat Experiences Until the Western Positions in Estonia were Reached (1944). By General der Infanterie Anton Grasser; 2 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. (Box 32)
  - D-132 Cavalry Brigade "Model" (1942). By Generalleutnant Karl-Friedrich von der Meden; 12 pp, 1 illus; OCMH multilith; 1947. Experiences of a special unit organized to engage in mobile warfare in all kinds of Russian terrain and weather. Describes organization, equipment, commitment in the Rzhev area. (Box 32)
  - D-133 Principles and Experiences of Position Warfare and Retrograde Movements. By General der Artillerie Walter Hartmann; 39 pp, 3 illus; 1947. Instructive examples of operations in Russia. (Box 32)
  - D-134 Engagements Fought by the 488th Infantry Regiment at the Stryanitsa and Desna Rivers (6-29 Sep. 1941). By Wilhelm Koehler; 29 pp, 4 maps; 1947. Interesting examples of attack, defense, and position warfare. (Box 32)
  - D-137 The Winter Battles of Rzhev, Vyazma, and Yuknov, 1941-42. By Generaloberst Otto Dessloch; 20 pp; 1947. Action west of Moscow. (Box 32)
  - D-138 The SS Panzergrenadier School. By Klaus Moelhoff; 17 pp; 1947. Organization and program of an officer candidate school; training of modern armored infantry. German combat doctrine at the end of the war. (Box 32)
  - D-139 The German Military Transportation System in Southern Russia, Rumania, Hungary (24 Nov. 1942-25 Mar. 1945). By Vico von Rieben; 42 pp, 8 illus, 2 maps; 1947. Southern Russia to 30 Mar. 1944. Use and limitations of the railway net in southern Russia. (Box 32)
  - D-140 Advance and Action of the 528th Infantry Regiment from 22 Jun. 1941 to Jan. 1942. By Generalmajor Heinrich Buercky; 36 pp, 9 illus; OCMH multilith; 1947. Combat in the Ukraine. (Box 32)
  - D-151 Fighting on the Narva Front: The Evacuation of Estonia and the Withdrawal to the Dvina. By General der Infanterie Anton Grasser; 18 pp, 2 illus; OCMH multilith; 1947. Operations of Armeeabteilung Narva. (Box 32)
  - D-152 Dniester Crossing (18 Jul. 1941). By Generalmajor Paul Schulz; 6 pp, 1 illus; 1947. Crossing at General Poetas; interesting battle narrative of an infantry regiment. (Not translated--1954.) (Box 32)
  - D-154 Experiences with Russian Methods of Warfare and their Utilization in Training at the Waffen-SS Panzer Grenadier School. By Klaus Moelhoff; 19 pp; 1947. Russian tactics, including changes and trends during the war years. (Box 32)
  - D-155 Comparison Between the Infantry Battalion and the Assault Battalion Developed by the Waffen-SS During the Course of the War. By Kurt Gropp; 10 pp; 1947. An analysis of infantry organization and tactics. (Box 32)
  - D-156 The Construction of a Strategic Defense Line in the East. Author unknown; 12 pp; 1947. A proposal made by General Olbricht early in 1942. Requirements of manpower and material. (Box 32)
  - D-157 Protection of the Supply Lines in the Southern Ukraine. By Generalleutnant (Lw) Ludwig Keiper; 12 pp; 1947. Protection of rail lines from partisan action. (Box 32)
  - D-162 German Night Fighters in the Mediterranean. By General der Flieger Josef Kammhuber; 65 pp; 1947. (Box 32)
  - D-166 Report on the Fighting of Kampfgruppe Lang (10th Pz Div) in Tunisia. By Oberst Rudolf Lang; 19 pp, 1 illus; 1947. Defensive fighting at Mezzouna-Maknessy, March-April 1943. (See also MS # D-173.) (Box 32)
  - D-173 Battles of Kampfgruppe Lang in Tunisia (10th Pz Div). By Oberst Rudolf Lang; 37 pp; 8 illus; 1947. Part I: Dec. 1942 to 1 Mar. 1943. Recollections of Colonel Lang, commander of the 69th Panzer Grenadier Regiment. (See also MS # D-166.) (Box 32)
  - D-175 The Technical Training of Ordnance Personnel. By Generalmajor Gustav Diesterweg; 10 pp; 1947. A survey of emergency courses undertaken in Germany. (Box 32)
  - D-177 International Law and Germany's Economic Warfare at Sea. By Admiralrichter Dr. Curt Eckhardt; 33 pp; 1947. A justification of Germany's attitude towards unrestricted submarine warfare. (Box 32)
  - D-178 Officer Procurement in the Waffen-SS (Reception, Processing and Training). By SS Generalmajor Werner Doerffler-Schuband; 15 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. See also MS # D-110. (Box 32)
  - D-179 Flak in Coastal and Air Defense: The Atlantic Wall. By General der Flakartillerie Eugen Weissmann; 37 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. The defense of coastal waters and installations against attack from the air. (Box 32)
  - D-183 255th Infantry Division (Jun.-Nov. 1941). By Generalleutnant Walter Friedrich Poppe; 25 pp, 3 illus; 1947. Advance into Russia. (Not translated--1954.) (Box 32)
  - D-184 Campaign of the 255th Infantry Division East and South of Temkino (Dec. 1941-Apr. 1942). By Generalleutnant Walter Friedrich Poppe; 21 pp, 5 illus; 1947. (Box 32)
  - D-185 Artillery in Swamps and Ice. By Generalleutnant Karl Prager; 14 pp; 1947. Performance of German artillery in northern Russia. (Box 32)
  - D-186 Experiences in the Medical Service of a Motorized SS Div. in 1941-42 in Russia. By Oskar Hock; 27 pp; 1947. In the Demjansk pocket; comments by a division surgeon on medical problems. (Box 33)
  - D-187 71st Infantry Regiment (22 Jun.-26 Jul. 1941). By Generalleutnant Wilh. Thomas; 18 pp; 1947. Capture of Smolensk, 15 Jul. 1941. (Box 33)
  - D-188 XLII Corps in the Relief of Kovel (19 Mar.-5 Apr. 1944). By General der Infanterie Franz Mattenklott; 10 pp, 2 illus; OCMH multilith; 1947. (Box 33)
  - D-189 The Pomeranian Battle and the Command in the East. By Generaloberst Erhard Raus; 54 pp, 2 maps; 1947. Conferences with Himmler and a report to Hitler (13 Feb. to 9 Mar. 1945). An account of fighting east of the Oder. (Box 33)
  - D-191 Commitment of Flak and Fighters to Protect the German Routes of Supply in Italy (1944-45). By General der Flieger Erich Ritter von Pohl; 11 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. (Box 33)
  - D-204 Employment of Panzer Units in Central Italy in 1944, and Peculiarities Thereof. By Generalmajor Martin Schmidt; 5 pp; 1947. Tactics employed in the Anzio area. (Box 33)
  - D-207 Organization of the Po River Crossings (1 Jan.-30 Mar. 1945). By Generalmajor Richard Baumgartner; 19 pp, 1 illus, 1 map. (Box 33)
  - D-208 Organization and Activity of Coastal Artillery in the Italian Theater of Operations (1943-1944). By Generalmajor Hans Moench; 24 pp; 1947. (Box 33)
  - D-216 The Operations under the Command of Marshal Graziani Prior to the Arrival of the German Troops (Aug.-Sep. 1940). By Oberst Heinen Heggenreiner; 22 pp; 1947. Personal observations of the German liaison officer in North Africa. Incomplete. (Box 33)
  - D-217 Italo-German Cooperation in Italian North Africa. By Oberst Heinz Heggenreiner; 15 pp; 1947. Visit with Marshal Balbo in May 1940; describes general conditions in Italian North Africa before the outbreak of war. (Box 33)
  - D-222 The Operations of LVI Panzer Corps from 18 Feb. to 18 Mar. 1945. By General der Infanterie Rudolf Koch Etpach; 20 pp, 1 illus; 1947. Combat in Silesia. (Box 33)
  - D-223 Commitment of the 183d Infantry Division. By Generalleutnant Benignus Dippold; 24 pp, 1 illus; 1947. From East Prussia to Yelnya(Aug.-Oct. 1941). Instructive lessons in attack and defense. (Box 33)
  - D-225 Advance of an SS Division (Motorized). By Generalmajor der Waffen- SS Karl Herrmann; 10 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. To Lake llmen, Jun.- Aug. 1941. (Box 33)
  - D-226 German Heavy Armor. By Rolf Moebius; 9 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. A comparison with Russian armor and methods. (See also MS # C-033.) (Box 33)
  - D-228 Russian Artillery in the Engagements Around Modlin and German Countermeasures. By SS Generalmajor Kurt Brasack; 5. pp; 1947. A short survey of Russian and German artillery tactics. (Box 33)
  - D-230 Operations of the 15th Waffen SS Grenadier Division (Jan.-Feb. 1945). By Adolf Ax; 26 pp, 2illus; 1947. Operations of a division of Latvian SS volunteers, from the Netze River at Nakel to the Bromberg Canal. (Box 33)
  - D-232 Condition of Railways in the Baltic Countries During the Advance of Eighteenth Army to Leningrad. By Generalmajor Hans Schittnig; 25 pp; OCMH mulfilah; 1947. A technical and historical report. Also included in MS # T-17. (Box 33)
  - D-233 Combat Experience in Estonia up to the Time the Estonian West Line was Reached. By General der Infantery Anton Grosser; 2 pp; 1947. (Box 33)
  - D-234 I Air Corps in the Kuban Bridgehead and the Crimea While Supporting Army Group A in Defensive Operations (24 Jun.-15 Nov. 1943). By Generalleutnant (Lw) Karl Ångerstein; 15 pp; 1947. (Box 33)
  - D-237 XXIII Corps (Oct. 1941-Mar. 1942). By Oberstleutnant Dietrich Lemcke; 18 pp, 2 illus; 1947. Supply in Russia, particularly by air. (Box 33)
  - D-239 Forced Crossing of the Bug River. Advance Thorough the Russian Border Defenses, and Capture of the Fortress of Brest-Litovsk. By Generalleutnant Friedrich John; 12 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. The 45th Infantry Division. (Box 33)
  - D-240 Advance and Battles of the 110th Infantry Division (Ninth Army) from the German Border to the Area West of Kallin (Jun.-Nov. 1941). By Generalmajor Heinz Gaede; 10 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. (Box 33)
  - D-241 Closing the 40-km. Gap. Between Army Group North and Army Group Center (Nov. 1942-Mar. 1943). By General der Pioniere Otto Tiemann; 7 pp, 2 illus; 1947. (Box 33)
  - D-243 Operations of the 112th Mountain Artillery Regiment (3d Mountain Division) in the Nikopol Bridgehead (29 Oct. 1943-16 Feb. 1944). By Hans Kreppel; 26 pp; 1947. (Box 33)
  - D-247 German Preparations for the Attack Against Russia. By Generalleutnant Curt Cuno; 13 pp, 1 illus; OCMH multilith; 1947. Crossing of the Bug River by 17th Panzer Division on the first day of the campaign. (Box 33)
  - D-248 Tactics of Mobile Units. Operations of the 5th SS Panzergrenadier Division "Wiking" at Rostov and the Maikop Oilfields (Summer 1942). By General der Waffen-SS Felix Steiner; 28 pp, 1 map, 1947. (Box 33)
  - D-252 Reich Labor Service (1939). By Reichsarbeitsführer Konstantin Hierl; 5pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. Activity with Third Army in the Polish campaign. A short historical account with comments on organization and commitment of construction troops in mobile warfare. (Box 33)
  - D-253 Antitank Defense in the East. By Generalleutnant Erich Schneider; 22 pp; 1947. Lessons from the fighting in autumn 1941. (Box 33)
  - D-254 Combat in the Caucasus Woods and Mountains During Autumn 1942. By Generalmajor Paul Schulz; 21 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. German and Russian tactics. (Box 33)
  - D-255 Advance of a Russian Cavalry Corps into the Rear of III Panzer Corps and Defense Against the Attack (6-10 Aug. 1941). By Generalleutnant Oskar Bluemm; 7 pp, 1 illus; OCMH multilith; 1947. (Box 33)
  - D-257 Protection of the Railroad Lines Brest-Lifiävsk-Gomel and Brest- Litovsk-Kovel (1943). By Heinz Krampf; 12 pp; 1947. Security measures against partisans. (Box 33)
  - D-258 Breakthrough of III Panzer Corps Through Deeply Echeloned Russian Defenses (Kharkov, Jul. 1943). By General der Panzertruppen Hermann Breith; 19 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. Contains valuable conclusions. (Box 33)
  - D-262 Supply By Air of the Demyansk Fortress During the Encirclement from 15 Feb. to 19 May 1942. By Generalmajor Friedrich Morzik; 23 pp; 1947. (Box 33)
  - D-264 123d Infantry Regiment in the Breakthrough Battle for the Parpach Position (8-11 Mar. 1942). By Generalmajor Guenter Meinhold; 6 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. (Box 33)
  - D-267 Russian Command in the Dubrovka Bridgehead, Lake Ladoga Front (April 1942). By General der Artillerie Herbert Loch; 13 pp, 1 illus, OCMH multilith; 1947. Organization and tactics of a Russian task force in the defense. (Box 33)
  - D-268 Combat Orders. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 15 pp; 1947. Psychological aspects of giving orders. (Box 33)
  - D-271 The Battle of Stalingrad. Signal Communications in the Pocket of Stalingrad and Communications with the Outside. By Generalmajor Wilhelm Arnold; 11 pp; 1947. By the Sixth Army signal officer; of historical and technical interest. (Box 33)
  - D-277 Regiment in the Attack Through Snow-Covered Primeval Forests (Jan. 1942). By Generalmajor Karl Rein; 23 pp, 1 illus; OCMH multilith; 1947. Lessons in small unit tactics. (Box 33)
  - D-281 The Last Russian Offensive, 1945: XXVII Corps Sector. By General der Artillerie Maximilian Felzmann; 49 pp, 7 illus; OCMH multilith; 1947. Narew-Graudenz-Danzig area, 28 Dec. 1944 to 27 Mar. 1945. A 1948. colorful historical account, including excellent sketch maps. (Box 33)
  - B-300 The Second Encirclement of Brody, (Jul. 1944). By Generalleutnant Wolfgang Lange; 22 pp, 1 illus; 194. Encirclement and breakout of Korpsgruppe C. A brief, dramatic report of this little known engagement. (Box 34)